Leszek¹ Pietrzak

Birthday: January 21st, 1987

Current location: CET Timezone

Nationality: Polish

Phone: skype:smutnyleszek

E-mail: leszek@magicznyleszek.xyz **Website**: github.com/magicznyleszek

Favourite color: black ¹if in doubt, try "lesheck"

I am a creator, I always loved building something new: be it through writing, drawing or coding. As for frontend development, I love that my work can be experienced live in the browser and that I can publish anything in just a few minutes. The three values closest to my heart are: order, meaning and simplicity. I fear for the future of humanity, so I don't want to throw more senseless evil out there – I would love to take part in a meaningful, nature– and future–friendly projects. I try to maintain good work/life balance, so I avoid toxic environments.

Skills

I have strong frontend development skills with some backend experience. I can do identity design, UI design and illustration – I mainly use Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign. I am no stranger to Scrum, Kanban, recruitment, introducing new people into projects and copywriting. I'm familiar with all the OSs, but my favourite setup is MacOS with Atom.

Technologies I would love to work with: **TypeScript** or **ES6**, **Angular**, **React**, **NPM**, **cssnext** and **Jekyll**. I would also like to have **TDD**, **code reviews**, **pair programming** and good planning with estimations.

Some technologies I worked with: HTML (Twig), CSS (Compass, Sass, cssnext, BEM, MADCSS), JavaScript (TypeScript, CoffeeScript, ES6 [Babel], Angular, React, Alt, Backbone, Phaser,

Lodash, jQuery, TweenMax), TDD (Karma, Jasmine, PhantomJS, Sinopia), Grunt, NPM, Git, CEF, Jekyll, MySQL, PHP (Symfony2), Jira, Asana.

Employment

November 2014 - Present

Frontend Engineer @ GOG.com - Warsaw, Poland - gog.com/galaxy

My main responsibility was creating a frontend of GOG Galaxy desktop application. I also develop some webapps and take part in recruiting new developers and introducing them to the project. During work here I took part in launching GOG Galaxy and creating The Witcher 3 game.

Technologies: TypeScript, ES6, Angular, Lodash, TDD (Karma, Jasmine, PhantomJS), Twig, Sass, BEM, MADCSS, CoffeeScript, Webpack, Grunt, NPM, Git, CEF, Jira, Asana

March 2007 - Present

Illustrator, Designer & Web Developer @ Self-employment - Worldwide - <u>leszekpietrzak.com</u>

I'm always open for small design and web jobs to give me opportunity to do something crazy and try something new. I also work on some open-source projects and tools on my spare time. Some cool web projects are:

<u>Hues</u> – color converter tool (React, Alt, ES6, RequireJS, Karma, cssnext, MADCSS)

<u>Fimder</u> – simple OMDb movie finder (Angular, ES6, Karma, cssnext, MADCSS)

<u>Mad Skeleton</u> – CSS boilerplate (Jekyll, Node, cssnext, MADCSS) <u>HashTabber</u> – hashchange-driven tabbed content switcher (ES5, Compass)

June 2013 – November 2014 **Web Designer & Frontend Developer** @ Clos Brothers – Warsaw, Poland – <u>closbrothers.pl</u> I was working in a small team delivering websites and webapps for big clients (Toyota) and smaller, educational ones, too (Museum of the History of Polish Jews, Silesian Risings Museum). Technologies: Angular, Phaser, jQuery, TweenMax, Compass, Jekyll, Twig, Symfony2, PHP, Grunt, Git, SVN.

October 2012 – July 2013

Graphic Designer & Web Developer @ Trewebs - Warsaw, Poland - trewebs.com

In this semi-startup, I was hired to design the UI and identity for diet app. As time went on, there were less design tasks and a need for developer arisen – as I was already familiar with HTML and CSS, I started to learn and work on some small web development projects.

Technologies: jQuery, Compass, Drupal, WordPress, PHP, MySQL

Education

September 2010 – September 2013

Graphic Design @ Wyższa Szkoła Nauk Humanistycznych i

Dziennikarstwa - Poznań, Poland

Licentiate degree (~BA) with highest score (5)

September 2007 – September 2010

Cultural Studies @ Wyższa Szkoła Nauk Humanistycznych i

Dziennikarstwa - Poznań, Poland

September 2006 – September 2007

Computer Science @ Adam Mickiewicz University – Poznań, Poland

Language skills

Polish - native

English - professional

German - basics

Toki Pona - basics

Interests

Evolution of life, existential philosophy, animal rights, traditional tattoo, ambient music, fantastic literature, American B-movies, Haiku, contemporary art and European comics.